BaseDePreguntas =[
    {
        pregunta:'  Hello , Susan. How are you?',
        respuesta:'I’m not very well',
        distractores:['I’m Mary’s brother','I’m going home','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:' ask about your current emotional state'
    },
    {
        pregunta:' What’s the matter? Have you got a headache?',
        respuesta:'No,I’ve got a toothache',
        distractores:['You’re welcome','No,thank you.I don’t want one','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:'headache means ’DOLOR DE CABEZA’ in spanish'
    },
    {
        pregunta:'What do you do?',
        respuesta:'I’m learning English',
        distractores:['I’m a dentist','I play tennis on Saturdays','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:'ask about the activity you do at the moment'
    },
    {
        pregunta:'Would you like to come to my house?',
        respuesta:'No,thanks.I want to go home',
        distractores:['Yes,I went home quickly','I play tennis on Saturdays','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:'ask about a possibility'
    },
    {
        pregunta:'Where do you come from?',
        respuesta:'Home',
        distractores:['Dublin','work','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:'ask about a place '
    },
    {
        pregunta:'When can we meet again?',
        respuesta:'Whenareyoufree?',
        distractores:['It was two days ago','Can you help me?','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:'is proposing a plan to meet again '
    },
    {
        pregunta:'I’m sorry I’m late',
        respuesta:'That’s all right',
        distractores:['You can’t go','There isn’t time','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:' ' 
    },
    {
        pregunta:'My brother is _____ engineer',
        respuesta:'an',
        distractores:['a',' ‐‐‐','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:'When the word begins with a consonant you must use ’A’'
    },
    {
        pregunta:'_______ 10 books on the shelf',
        respuesta:'There are',
        distractores:['There is','They are','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:'the noun is written in the plural'
    },
    {
        pregunta:'My dad doesn’t like golf',
        respuesta:'playing',
        distractores:['play','to playing','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:'Golf is a sport whose objective is to introduce a ball into the holes'
    },
    {
        pregunta:'______ your brother speak Spanish?',
        respuesta:'Does',
        distractores:['Is','Do','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:'dont forget the third person on the verb '
    },
    {
        pregunta:'Joe _____ at school last week',
        respuesta:'wasn’t',
        distractores:['didn’t be','isn’t','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:'the verb is in past simple'
    },
    {
        pregunta:' Richard’s brother _______ to work yesterday because he was ill',
        respuesta:'didn’t go',
        distractores:['doesn’t go','didn’twent','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:'The expression can only have a verb in the past'
    },
    {
        pregunta:'Jennifer got married ______ 1998',
        respuesta:'in',
        distractores:['on','at','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:' IN, ON and AT are used to refer to the location of things in a given space'
    },
    {
        pregunta:'You house is _____ than our flat',
        respuesta:'bigger',
        distractores:['more big','more bigger','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:' The comparative is used to compare differences between the two objects it modifies (larger, smaller, faster, higher).'
    },
    {
        pregunta:'My bike is very old.I’m going a _____ new one soon',
        respuesta:'to buy',
        distractores:['buy','to will buy','I don’t know'],
        ayuda:' '
    }
    
]
    
